AMIT KUMAR

amitjha.manipal@gmail.com +91 9739315373

Platform Architect – Reactive Application

in

https://www.linkedin.com/in/amit-kumar-5b2b111a/

A pragmatic who is passionate about technology, learning new things, and helping others to work better and more effectively. I have more than 11+ years of experience designing and delivering software systems in a wide variety of domains including automotive, aerospace, healthcare. I enjoy helping people transition to agile approaches for developing software and have fun doing it

SPECIALITIES

Microservices, Reactive Systems, Reactive Programming, Distributed Systems, Fast Data Architecture, Message-Driven Architecture, Event-Driven Architecture, Resilience, Elasticity, Scalability, High-Availability, Concurrent Programming, Functional Programming, Object-Oriented Programming, Aspect-Oriented Programming, Domain-Driven Design, Open Source Strategy, Business Models, and Community Building.

SKILL

- Microservices: Akka, lagom, Play Framework, Kafka Alpakka
- Functional Programming: Scala, Scala.js, Java and other languages
- Streaming engines: Akka Streams, and Kafka Streams, Alpakka Stream
- **Reactive Systems**: Event-driven, scalable, resilient, and responsive applications using the Lightbend Reactive Platform, especially Akka
- **Distributed Systems**: Polyglot Persistence, Cassandra, Janus Graph, Kafka Stream, Akka Persistence
- Message-Driven Architecture: Akka actor Model asynchronous.
- Event-Sourcing CQRS: DDD, Akka Persistence

- Cloud Orchestration: Akka cluster, Kubernetes DC/OS, minikube deployment pipeline, AWS.
- Security: Microservice web-gateway JWT authentication, RBAC authorization.
- User Experience: React.js redux, flow, bootstrap, WebSocket Rest-Api: Akka Http, Play, lagom postman
- Software Development Lifecycle: Agile Scrum Team Leadership: Mentor, Community Building

EXPERIENCE

01/2016 to current

Platform Architect

Intercax Technologies. - Bangalore India

- Design and implementation of a distributed system architecture based on event sourcing and highly scalable, resilient, reactive, Cloud native microservice platform.
- Design/Development of a Kafka Alpakka stream fast data connector for enterprise application.
- Responsible for formulation of solution and strategy keeping focus of reactive design principle.
- Evangelist for new age technology adoption in team and in corporate strategy.
- Responsible for devising strategy for product deployment, migration for cloud and on-premise

11/2013 to 01/2016

Solution Architect

Tata Consultancy Services Ltd. - Bangalore India

- Design and implementation customer experience management system for major healthcare company
- Designing the integration pipeline for issue management of product data in Windchill PLM system
- Responsible for devising strategy for migration legacy product issue data to CEM System
- Responsible for moderating business stake holder on requirement and technical specification
- Designing implementation strategy for automated customer issue creation based on user complain as per FDA regulation

12/2010 to 11/2013

Sr. Software Engineer

Volvo India Pvt Ltd. Bangalore India

- Requirement Analysis of new change Request toward PDMLink functionality. Provide end to end delivery of such request co-coordinating with development testing and AO team.
- Responsible as Volvo site India Maintenance Assignment co-coordinator.
- Responsible for investigating, devising roadmap new interface to enable PDMLink communication with other enterprise application.
- Designing and Developing Services, Adapter, Listener to take care of PDMLink proactive communication with other application.

Last Updated: 5/11/2019

AMIT KUMAR

amitjha.manipal@gmail.com +91 9739315373

Platform Architect – Reactive Application

in

https://www.linkedin.com/in/amit-kumar-5b2b111a/

- Devising solution involving info engine, toolkit etc. to take care of customized batch process in plotting publishing export import.
- Developing custom JSP page to facilitate customer data validation and custom information.
- Responsible for system performance, auditing of PDMLink infrastructure
- Responsible for runtime troubleshooting of PDMLink Infrastructure to uphold our commitment of SLA/OLA to customer.
- Responsible for coordinating with AO team in various PDMLink infrastructure related maintenance and housekeeping activity.
- Devising methodology performing audit on PDMLink infrastructure/resource utilization and suggesting action/strategy to do away bottleneck.
- Responsible for devising strategy for knowledge sharing session on PDMLink and related process to enable cross function knowledge exchange between PD/AD team in site BLR
- Responsible for envisaging future resource, skill, expertise plan/strategy required for VPDM Project ramp up. Helping in assessing candidate skill as being part of interview panel.

05/2010 to 12/2010

Software Engineer

IBM INDIA Pvt. Ltd. Bangalore India

- Requirement Analysis of Business Process Mapping, Application, integration with ERP and Multi MCAD tool
- Developing info engine services for publishing enterprise metadata in ERP
- Developing custom JSP page to facilitate customer specific report using info engine Talib.
- Developing custom JSP, PL-SQL script for object count, Change management report.
- Developing Windchill Api based custom code to modify soft attribute, lifecycle state
- Developing Data base query to get, file size, vault location, most commonly used document, part, purgeable object etc.
- Developing Unix script to monitor method server performance and reporting.
- Responsible for weekly and monthly maintenance and health check activity using Windchill Utility.
- Planning Executing db. aphelion backup and disaster recovery,
- Performing Administration on Workflow, vaulting, Replication
- Performing health check of tomcat and Apache and monitoring performance.
- Analyzing security vulnerability and its remediation as per IBM standard policy.
- Responsible for coordination with PTC for SPR & temp patch.
- Performing rehosting/cloning of production to dev and QA environment.
- Responsible for testing & documentation of custom functionality while planning for upgrade/enhancement.
- Responsible for client interaction and seeking domain know how for process mapping.
- Planning hardware requirement and sizing.

08/2007 to 05/2010

Application Developer

Tata Consultancy Services Ltd. - Bangalore India.

- Requirement Analysis of Business Process Mapping, Manufacturing Publishing Requirement, Information flow across another PLM
- Study the Out-Of-Box/Custom Pro-e/Toolkit integration with Windchill.
- Mitigating the Road Map for Custom Publishing through Windchill Object Adapter.
- Customizing Windchill Cad Agent Worker Class for publishing requirement.
- Designing, customizing and Testing OOTB Publish Block workflow for publishing requirement.
- Designing, Testing and customizing Approval/Review workflow for mapping Cummins change management process.
- Designing and customizing the Windchill Loader to upload Office and AutoCAD Document in bulk.
- Designing and customizing Windchill for inflow/outflow of metadata to other PLM system.
- Responsible for formation and leading a team of three members in fulfilling the above-mentioned requirement.
- Responsible for suggesting and mitigating a roadmap so that Cummins all manufacturing process get mapped to Windchill.
- Responsible for formulating strategy for Upgrading Windchill 8.0M030 to Windchill 9.1
- M040 with focus on risk area, production downtime, and rollback. Responsible for carrying out the WINDU, Upgrade Manager, and different healer script.
- Developed C++ platform tool to automate the extraction of data from legacy database.
- Developed legacy API application tool to validate the extracted data.
- Developed java platform tool to call different PLM system environment during the extraction, staging and import of data.
- Developed C++ based TCE ITK tool to create object in bulk in TeamCenter PLM.

Last Updated: 5/11/2019

AMIT KUMAR

amitjha.manipal@gmail.com +91 9739315373

Platform Architect – Reactive Application in

https://www.linkedin.com/in/amit-kumar-5b2b111a/

- Developed oracle utility to process the data in staging area.
- Developed java platform tool to automate the import of data through CAD MANAGER.

ACTIVITIES AND HONORS

- Dfsdsdgsdgdgdsg
- Dfsdsdgsdgdgdsg
- Sdg
- Sdsdgs
- Sdgds
- Sdgsdg
- Dfhdfhfdh
- Dfhfdh
- Dgdfhdfh

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

2007

Bachelor or Engineering: Mechanical Manipal Institute of Technology. - India.

- Integrated Learning program covering PCMM, Project Management, System Analysis, Design, Implementation, Technical Review, Quality Management (iQMS), Team Skills, Six Sigma and Soft Skills etc.
- SOA-service oriented architecture
- PTC Pro-Intralink
- PTC Windchill
- SIEMENS TeamCenter

Last Updated: 5/11/2019 Page 3 of 3